<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>metabolism on Tianyi@Oxford</title>
    <link>/tags/metabolism.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in metabolism on Tianyi@Oxford</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/metabolism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic Modelling</title>
      <link>/lab/metabolic-modelling.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lab/metabolic-modelling.html</guid>
      <description>1 The Haldane Relationship 2 Control Points in A Simple Linear Pathway 3 Linear Pathway with Negative Feedback 3.1 Re-analyse the effect of \(K_i\) with constant flux 3.1.1 Repeat with Model 212 Model 112 was used. 1 The Haldane Relationship Using the “Parameter Scan” utility in Copasi (Figure 1.1), I collected steady state concentrations of ‘A’ and ‘B’ in \(5^4 = 625\) combinations of \(V_{max(f)}\), \(K_{m(p)}\), \(V_{max(r)}\), and \(K_{m(s)}\), where each parameter vary from \(1\times10^{-2}\) to \(1\times10^{2}\) in a logarithmic scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuel Selection During Exercise</title>
      <link>/tutorial/sensing-energy-status-during-exercise.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/sensing-energy-status-during-exercise.html</guid>
      <description>1 Introduction 2 Overview 2.1 Glycogen and Glucose 2.1.1 Blood Glucose 2.1.2 Regulation of Glycogenolysis 2.2 Fatty Acids 2.2.1 Adipose Tissue Lipolysis and Plasma NEFA 2.2.2 Intramuscular Triacylglycerol (IMTG) 2.2.3 Plasma TG (VLDL-TG) What effects do the intensity and duration of exercise have on fuel selection by mammalian muscle?
1 Introduction During exercise, glucose and fatty acids are the fuels used by the muscle. Their origin and relative contribution depend on the intensity and duration of exercise, as well as on characteristics of individuals such as the level of physical training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supplying Fuels to the Brain During Starvation</title>
      <link>/tutorial/supplying-fuels-to-the-brain-during-starvation.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/supplying-fuels-to-the-brain-during-starvation.html</guid>
      <description>Title: As starvation proceeds, how does the supply of fuels to the brain change? How is this change related to a requirement to conserve body protein?
Due to the blood-brain barrier, The human brain can only harness energy from catabolising either glucose or ketone bodies. Under normal circumstances, glucose of dietary origin is the predominant source of fuel for the brain. As starvation begins (during the postabsorptive phase), astrocytes in the brain break down their stored glycogen to supply fuel in the form of lactate to neurons, which is followed by hepatic glycogenolysis that continue to provide glucose for the brain for a short period.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
