<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>X-ray crystallography on Tianyi@Oxford</title>
    <link>/tags/x-ray-crystallography.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in X-ray crystallography on Tianyi@Oxford</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/x-ray-crystallography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Crystallography: A Case Study</title>
      <link>/tutorial/crystallography-a-case-study.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/crystallography-a-case-study.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction The Ca2+ selectivity of voltage-gated calcium (Cav) channels remained unclear. They were thought to use a ‘knock-off’ methanism which requires multiple ion-binding cores, but mutational analyses supported a single high-affinity Ca2+ binding site. This paradox is explained by the mechanism proposed in this article, based on the crystal structures of CavAb channels.
Methods In this study, the authors created several mutants of bacterial Nav channel NavAb by site directed mutagenesis using QuickChange at the selectivity filter region1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing The Quality Structural Models</title>
      <link>/tutorial/assessing-structural-models.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/assessing-structural-models.html</guid>
      <description>1 The Essence of X-Ray Crystallography 2 Assessing the Quality of A Structure During Model Building and Refinement 2.1 R and Rfree 2.2 Reciprocal-Space Refinement: Refinement by least squares 2.3 Real-Space Refinement: Map Fitting 3 Assessing Quality After Automatic Model Building and Refinement 3.1 Density fit analysis and local geometry validation 3.1.1 Structural parameters: bond length, bond angle, chirality, planarity, and dihedral angles 3.1.2 Torsional Angles and Ramachandran Plot 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electron Microscopy and X-Ray Crystallography</title>
      <link>/tutorial/electron-microscopy-and-x-ray-crystallography.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/electron-microscopy-and-x-ray-crystallography.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning objectives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand the methodological principle of electron microscopy in its different applications (e.g. TEM, SEM, tomography, single-particle), and X-ray crystallography  To be able to evaluate, which method of structural analysis would be most feasible with which kind of biological specimen (e.g. whole cells, viruses, protein complexes, peptides).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To gain a conception of the resolution ranges attainable by EM methods as compared to X-ray crystallography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be aware of the computational methods that combine EM maps and crystallogrographic data&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protein Structure and Function</title>
      <link>/tutorial/protein-structure-and-function.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/protein-structure-and-function.html</guid>
      <description>Choose 3 structural papers. They can be crystallography, NMR, CryoEM etc. Explain why the protein is important and what the structure tells you about function (why you find it interesting) but most importantly go to the methods section (it may be supplementary information especially if you choose high profile paper) and explain how the protein was purified. The techniques will be those covered in Matt Higgins&amp;rsquo; lecture series. Bring notes no essay.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
