<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NMR on Tianyi@Oxford</title>
    <link>/tags/nmr.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in NMR on Tianyi@Oxford</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/nmr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Assessing The Quality Structural Models</title>
      <link>/tutorial/assessing-structural-models.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/assessing-structural-models.html</guid>
      <description>1 The Essence of X-Ray Crystallography 2 Assessing the Quality of A Structure During Model Building and Refinement 2.1 R and Rfree 2.2 Reciprocal-Space Refinement: Refinement by least squares 2.3 Real-Space Refinement: Map Fitting 3 Assessing Quality After Automatic Model Building and Refinement 3.1 Density fit analysis and local geometry validation 3.1.1 Structural parameters: bond length, bond angle, chirality, planarity, and dihedral angles 3.1.2 Torsional Angles and Ramachandran Plot 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NMR</title>
      <link>/tutorial/nmr.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/nmr.html</guid>
      <description>SAQ Write brief notes on the chemical shift, the nuclear Overhauser enhancement effect (NOE), the relaxation times T1 and T2, and the spin-spin coupling constant (J) with an emphasis on how these can provide information about the structure and dynamics of biological molecules.
Chemical Shift: NMR applies RF wave to induce resonance with the precession frequency, \(\omega=\gamma (B_0-B_S)\), where \(B_0\) is the constant magnetic field strength on the \(z\) axis, \(B_S\) is the magnetic field strength shilded by electrons around the nucleus and \(\gamma\) is the magnetogyric ratio (depending of the identity of the nucleus).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
