<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>plant metabolism on Tianyi@Oxford</title>
    <link>/tags/plant-metabolism.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in plant metabolism on Tianyi@Oxford</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/plant-metabolism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Redox-Based Modulation of Enzyme Activity</title>
      <link>/tutorial/redox-based-modulation-of-enzyme-activity.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/redox-based-modulation-of-enzyme-activity.html</guid>
      <description>Presentation see here
Geigenberger, Peter, Ina Thormählen, Danilo M. Daloso, and Alisdair R. Fernie. 2017. “The Unprecedented Versatility of the Plant‎ Thioredoxin System.” Trends in Plant Science 22 (3): 249–62. https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tplants.2016.12.008.
Hägglund, Per, Christine Finnie, Hiroyuki Yano, Azar Shahpiri, Bob B. Buchanan, Anette Henriksen, and Birte Svensson. 2016. “Seed Thioredoxin H.” Biochimica et Biophysica Acta (BBA) - Proteins and Proteomics 1864 (8): 974–82. https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbapap.2016.02.014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Photosynthesis by Photorespiratory Bypasses</title>
      <link>/tutorial/improving-photosynthesis-by-photorespiratory-bypasses.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/improving-photosynthesis-by-photorespiratory-bypasses.html</guid>
      <description>1 Attempts to Inhibit Photorespiration and Improve Specificity of Rubisco 2 Bypassing Photorespiration 2.1 Implementing The Bacterial Glycerate Pathway 2.2 Inhibition of the Glycolate Transporter 3 Conclusion References Discuss the feasibility and desirability of improving photosynthesis in higher plants through the use of photorespiratory bypasses.
Plants and algae use the Calvin cycle to capture inorganic carbon (as CO2) and use ATP and NADPH generated in light reactions to convert it to organic carbon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic Manipulation of the Calvin Cycle</title>
      <link>/tutorial/genetic-manipulation-of-the-calvin-cycle.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/genetic-manipulation-of-the-calvin-cycle.html</guid>
      <description>1 Introduction 1.1 Rubisco Does not Exert Much Control on the Flux of the Calvin Cycle Unless in Special Conditions 2 Other Enzymes that Catalyse Irreversible Reactions 3 Plastid Aldolase as an ‘Non-Regulated’ Enzyme Exerts a Greater Control than Rubisco on the Rate of Photosynthesis 4 Transketolase Directly Controls not Only Calvin Cycle but Also Other Pathways 5 Conclusion To what extent has genetic manipulation of the Calvin cycle forced the reappraisal of our understanding of the control of metabolic pathways in plants?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coordination of PS I and PS II</title>
      <link>/tutorial/coordination-of-ps-i-and-ps-ii.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/coordination-of-ps-i-and-ps-ii.html</guid>
      <description>1 Background 2 Why is Coordination between Photosystems I and II Needed 3 How is Coordination between PS-I and PS-II Achieved 3.1 The Role of the Plastoquinone Pool 3.2 Reversible Redistribution of LHC-II 3.3 Transcriptional Regulation 3.3.1 How does SIG1 phosphorylation confer phhotosystem promoter specificity? 4 Conclusion References Why do plants co-ordinate the relative activities of Photosystems I and II and how is this co-ordination achieved?
1 Background Photosystems I and II are photochemical complexes that harvest light energy to drive endergonic redox reactions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
