<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>physics on Tianyi@Oxford</title>
    <link>/tags/physics.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in physics on Tianyi@Oxford</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/physics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>NMR</title>
      <link>/tutorial/nmr.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/nmr.html</guid>
      <description>SAQ Write brief notes on the chemical shift, the nuclear Overhauser enhancement effect (NOE), the relaxation times T1 and T2, and the spin-spin coupling constant (J) with an emphasis on how these can provide information about the structure and dynamics of biological molecules.
Chemical Shift: NMR applies RF wave to induce resonance with the precession frequency, \(\omega=\gamma (B_0-B_S)\), where \(B_0\) is the constant magnetic field strength on the \(z\) axis, \(B_S\) is the magnetic field strength shilded by electrons around the nucleus and \(\gamma\) is the magnetogyric ratio (depending of the identity of the nucleus).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biophysical Techniques</title>
      <link>/tutorial/biophysical-techniques.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/biophysical-techniques.html</guid>
      <description>You have expressed and purified a protein in a recombinant system. How would you confirm that the protein was the one expected from the DNA sequence. (ESI-MS) How would you determine that the protein was folded and its solution behaviour. (CD, Thermofluor, Intrinsic fluorescence, DSC, SEC MALS, AUC, DLS) How can we quantify the binding between two macromolecules? Discuss how you could use the following techniques to determine a KD for an interaction? What are their limitations in practice? What would decide which techniques you could apply to an interaction? (Surface Plasmon resonance, Fluorimetry/Fluorescence anisotropy, Microscale thermophoresis (MST), Isothermal titration calorimetry (ITC), Stopped flow, NMR, AUC) References: Use Campbell&amp;rsquo;s Biophysical Techniques; for MST use Wienken et al 2010 Nature Communications 10.1038/ncomms1093</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
