<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>developmental biology on Tianyi@Oxford</title>
    <link>/tags/developmental-biology.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in developmental biology on Tianyi@Oxford</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/developmental-biology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Has Ras Signalling Been Studied in C. Elegans</title>
      <link>/tutorial/how-has-ras-signalling-been-studied-in-c-elegans.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/how-has-ras-signalling-been-studied-in-c-elegans.html</guid>
      <description>1 Introduction 2 The Big Picture: Components of the C. elegans EGF-Ras-MAPK Pathway Involved in Vulva Induction 3 Techniques for Studying EGFR-Ras-MAPK Signalling and Vulva Induction 3.1 Forward Genetics and Reverse Genetics 3.1.1 In Early Experiments, Forward Genetics Methods were Used Entensively 3.1.2 RNAi and Reverse Genetics Since 1998 3.2 Observing Cell Fates 3.2.1 Microscopic Analysis 3.2.2 Transcriptional Reporters 3.3 Cross-Species Genomic Analysis Reveals Homology and Helps to Elucidate Roles of Proteins with Greater Accuracy 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Point of Studying Developmental Biology</title>
      <link>/tutorial/what-is-the-point-of-studying-developmental-biology.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/what-is-the-point-of-studying-developmental-biology.html</guid>
      <description>Title: What is the point of studying developmental biology?
Link to presentation
The main theme of developmental biology is the fate determination of cells, their division, differention and death, as well as the resulting higher level processes, including morphogenesis and organ formation. I’ll illustrate how this knowledge can help with preventive and public healthcare as well as modern medical research.
Prenatal Care (Preventing Teratogenesis) Teratogen and congenital anomaly According to the US’ National Research Council, ~3% of live births suffer from major developmental aberrations, ~70% of neonatal deaths are due to developmental defects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
